奇迹课程
采访嘉宾
玛莉安·威廉森
朱迪思·斯库奇·惠特森
杰拉德·詹波尔斯基
肯尼斯·霍布尼克博士
海伦·舒曼的文本由格莱尼斯·约翰斯朗读
I first saw
我第一次看到
a course in miracles on someone's coffee table.
奇迹课程是在一个人的咖啡桌上。
And I suppose nineteen seventy seven something like that.
我想那时大概是在1977年。
And I read the introduction
我读了导言，
and the introduction is a kind of astonishing thing.
导言中所描述的非常令人震惊。
I have it here.
我这里有导言的文本。
The introduction says:
在导言中说道:
This is a course in miracles. It is a required course.
"这是一门阐释奇迹的课程。是一门必修的课程。
Only the time you take it is voluntary.
只有投入的时间是随你的愿的。
Free will does not mean
随自己的意愿并不
that you can establish the curriculum.
表示着你可以自订课程。
It means only that you can elect what you want to take
这只表示在某段时间内你可以选择
at a given time.
自己所要学习的。
The course does not aim at teaching the meaning of love,
本课程的宗旨并非教你爱的真谛,
for that is beyond what can be taught.
因为那是无法传授的。
It does aim, however,
它旨在
at removing the blocks to the awareness of
清除使你感受不到
love's presence,
爱的那些障碍,
which is your natural inheritance.
而爱是你与生俱来的禀赋。
The opposite of love is fear,
与爱相对的是恐惧；
but what is all-encompassing can have no opposite.
但无所不容之境是没有对立的。
This course
因此，
can therefore be summed up very simply in this way:
本课程可以简单地归纳为下面这几句话:
Nothing real can be threatened.
凡是真实的，不受任何威胁；
Nothing unreal exists.
凡是不真实的，根本不存在。
Herein lies the peace of god.
上主的平安即在其中。"
I saw that. I read it.
我看到这本书并读了。
And I thought that was the most
我觉得这是我见过的
amazing piece of writing
最了不起的著作。
um to pick up a book and have the book tell you
拿起一本书，书里告诉你，
it's a required course.
这是一门必修课。
I mean
我的意思是
you go well who wrote it what is it who is telling me
很好，这是谁写的，是谁告诉我的，
that this book is a required course
这本书是必修课。
I was so intrigued by that.
我对此很感兴趣。
I read one page and that one page of reading
我读了一页，在读这一页的过程中，
and I heard for the first time in a little inner voice
第一次听到有一个小小的内心声音，
that said:
说道:
Physician healed life self, this is your way home.
"医师治愈自己的生命，这是你回家的路"。
And I had the most amazing experience of
我经历了最美好的时光，
feeling a sense of oneness with the whole world
感受到与整个世界的一体感，
that there was absolutely no separation that
完全没有分离，
there was only love
只有爱。
And a real feeling that I was to be of service to god,
还有一种真正的感觉，觉得自己是在为上主服务，
my whole life would be changed
我的整个人生都会改变，
and to be a life of giving and
一生都在奉献和
life of being of service
服务生命。
I really couldn't understand that
我真的无法理解这一点，
but it was a very deep penetrating feeling.
但这是一个非常深刻的渗透性的感觉。
And I became a student of course
于是我一成为了这门课程的学生，
fight it all the way
为消化它不断奋斗，
couldn't deal with the thickness of the course
不过我无法消化这么厚的课程，
let alone its christian terminology
更不用说其中的基督教术语了。
And yet there was something about the course that just
然而，这个课程有一些东西
compelled me to go on.
迫使我继续学习下去。
The spiritual genesis of the international best seller
国际畅销书《奇迹课程》
a course in miracles
的灵性起源
is both extraordinary and inspiring
既非凡又鼓舞人心，
the self study three book course was dictated by an inner voice
三本自学课程的书籍是由内心声音所决定的，
and it is profoundly changed the lives of countless
它深刻地改变了世界上
people the world alone.
无数人的生活。
Spread mainly by word of mouth,
主要通过口口相传,
its principles of thus far been known
其原则迄今为止
only to its students.
只有其学员知道。
But now its transformational teachings of
但现在这部影片将探索这部课程
love，forgiveness，inner peace and wisdom will be explored.
关于爱、宽恕、内心平安和智慧的变革性教义。
Communicating the correct meaning of the course
传达课程的正确含义
rests largely with Dr kenneth Wapnick,
在很大程度上取决于肯尼斯·霍布尼克博士
president of the foundation for a course in miracles.
他是奇迹基金会的主席。
In a recent television interview
在最近的一次电视采访中，
he gave an enlightening overview of the course.
他给了我们一个有启发性的课程概述。
It's a form of spiritual cycle therapy
这是一种在基督教的背景下呈现给我们的
that comes to us in a christian context.
精神循环疗法。
As you mentioned at the beginning
正如你在开头提到的,
its author is Jesus
它的作者是耶稣，
but it's a christianity
但它实际上
that is practically nothing to do with the traditional
与2000年的传统的
teachings of 2000 years
基督教教义毫无关系，
certainly has nothing to do with the Jesus of the Bible.
当然也与圣经中的耶稣毫无关系。
Its principle messages is forgiveness
这本书的主要内容是宽恕，
and that the way that we remember
这是我们忆起我们的身份是
our identity is god's children
上主之子的方式，
and realize that in his eyes we are all one
并认出在祂的眼中我们是宽恕彼此的
to forgive each other.
一体生命。
It basically is a self study course in the sense
从某种意义上说，它基本上是一门自学课程，
that you don't need anyone outside
你不需要外在的
the teacher or the guru
老师或导师，
as it were would be jesus or the holy spirit
因为耶稣或圣灵
who guide us day by day.
每天都在指导着我们。
Our lives in this world are seen as a classroom
我们可以把在这个世界上的生活
basically in which we learn
视为课堂，在这里学习
our holy spirits lessons are forgiveness.
圣灵提供给我们的宽恕课程。
And again as I mentioned is
正如我所提到的，
by undoing all of the our feelings of inadequacy,
通过化解我们所有的匮乏感，
our feelings of guilt, our anxieties
我们的内疚感以及我们的焦虑，
which is what forgiveness brings about，
这就是宽恕带来的结果，
that the love of god which is present in all of us
即让人们忆起存在于我们
is allowed to be remembered.
所有人身上的上主之爱。
There is a massive effort going on in this society
在这个社会中，我认为在整个世界范围内，
and I think throughout the world
都在进行大规模的努力，
to retrieve some lost part of ourselves.
以找回我们自己失去的一些部分。
And a course in miracles is part of that effort.
而奇迹课程就是这种努力的一部分。
-*- 奇迹课程的灵性起源 -*-
A course in miracles contains
奇迹课程涵盖了
a whole philosophy for living in our times.
生活在我们这个时代的全部哲学。
The course was born when an inner voice spoke to
这门课程诞生于1965年，
Dr Helen Schucman in 1965,
当时有一个内在声音与海伦·舒曼博士交谈,
While she was working at Columbia University.
那时海伦在哥伦比亚大学工作。
Helen was a highly respected
海伦是一位备受尊敬的
research psychologist and associate professor
研究心理学家和副教授，
who worked with Dr William Thetford,
曾与威廉·塞福博士合作过，
a professor of medical psychology
塞福博士当时在久负盛名的
at the prestigious Columbia University's College of
哥伦比亚大学内外科医学院
of Physicians and Surgeons.
担任医学心理学教授。
In her unpublished autobiography,
海伦于1981年2月9日去世，
Helen who died on February 9th, 1981,
在她未出版的自传中，
described her reactions to her job
她描述了她对工作的反应
and the highly stressful situations that existed there.
以及在那里的高度紧张的情况。
I was a psychologist educator
我是一个理论上保守
conservative in theory and atheistic in belief
以及无神论的心理学教育家，
I was working in a prestigious
我在一个享有盛誉且
and highly academic setting
学术水平很高的环境中工作，
and the job was ghastly at first.
起初这份工作很糟糕。
The hospital didn't provide space for our projects
医院没有为我们的项目提供空间，
and when we were finally housed in the new research building,
当我们最终进驻新的研究大楼时,
it was the most difficult situation of my professional life.
那是我职业生涯中最困难的时刻。
The work was oppressive
这项工作很压抑，
and carried out in an atmosphere of suspicion and competitiveness.
是在充满猜疑和竞争的气氛中进行。
And interpersonal harmony was depressingly lacking.
人际关系的和谐令人沮丧地缺乏。
Then something happened
然后发生了一些事情，
that triggered a chain of events
引发了一连串
I could never have predicted.
我从未预料到的事情。
We had worked together for a number of years
我们一起工作了很多年，
actually from 1958 until the summer of 1965
实际上从1958年直到1965年夏天，
with a good deal of improvement in terms of the organization
当时医院的心理学部门在
of the psychology department at the hospital,
组织方面有了很大的改进，
but we weren't really at peace.
但我们并没有真正平安下来。
And one day I gave Helen a little speech,
在1965年6月，
this was in June of 1965
有一天在我们开会前，
before we were going to a meeting.
我给海伦做了一个简短的演讲。
Essentially what I said is
从本质上讲，
there must be a better way
我所说的是必须有一种
of living and working in the world
更好的生活和工作方式
of handling our personal and professional
来处理我们的个人和
relationships and problems.
专业关系以及存在的问题。
And I'm determined to find it.
我下定决心去找出路。
This is kind of a long speech for me and
这对我来说是一个很长的演讲，
I remember feeling at the end of this that
我记得在演讲结束的时候，
Helen probably was going to laugh.
我感觉海伦可能会笑。
But to my amazement
但令我惊讶的，
quite the contrary,
恰恰相反,
she said, your absolutely right, Bill，
她说，"比尔，你说的完全正确，
we find this other way together.
我们一起来寻找出路。"
And that was the beginning of a joint commitment
这是我们两人
which the two of us made.
共同承诺的开始。
The summer of 1965 was
对我和海伦来说，
an extraordinary summer for both Helen and me
1965年的夏天在很多方面
in a number of ways.
都是非同寻常的。
Helen began to have
海伦开始有
a great deal of what you might call
大量可以称之
heightened visual imagery
为加强的视觉想象
or dream sequences,
或梦境序列,
she began to experience this with considerable clarity.
她开始非常清楚地体会到这一点。
And I suggested that she write down
我建议她把
these experiences as they occurred,
这些经历写下来,
because they seem to have something
因为它们似乎在
they were saying something very important
说一些很重要的事情，
even though we didn't know exactly what that was.
尽管我们当时并不知道那到底是什么。
One of those sequences involved being in a boat.
其中有一个在船上的情节。
The boat was moving slowly
小船沿着一条笔直的小运河
but easily along a very straight little canal.
缓慢而轻松地行驶。
There was just enough breeze to help the boat along.
微风刚好能吹拂小船前进。
I wonder if there is very treasure here
我不知道这里是否有很多宝藏，
I thought to myself dreamily.
我在梦中想着。
I shouldn't be surprised if there were.
如果有的话，我也不应该感到惊讶。
Then I noticed a long pole with a large hook on the end
然后我注意到船底有一根长长的竿子，
lying on the bottom of the boat,
一端有一个大钩子,
just the thing I thought
正如我所想的那样，
dropping the hook into the water
把鱼钩子扔进水里，
and reaching the pole down as far as I could.
然后尽可能远地把鱼竿伸到水里。
The hook caught something heavy
钩子钩住了什么沉重的东西，
and I raised it with difficulty.
我费了好大劲才把它捞上来。
It was an ancient treasure chest,
这是一个古老的宝箱,
the wood worn from the water
木头在水中浸泡后磨损，
and the bottom covered with seaweed.
底部覆盖着海草。
There was nothing in the chest but a large black book,
箱子里除了一本黑色的大本子外，什么都没有,
like the spring binders
这个本子就像用来
used for holding manuscripts or papers together.
装手稿或论文的活页夹。
On the spine, one word was written in gold,
书脊上写着一个金字,
the word was AESCULAPIUS.
即埃斯库拉庇乌斯。
The word was familiar,
这个词很熟悉,
but I could not remember what it meant.
但我当时不记得那是什么意思了。
When I looked it up,
当我查阅的时候,
I found that it was the name
我发现这是
of the Greek God of Healing.
古希腊医神的名字。
I saw the same book once more a few nights later,
几天后的晚上，我又在梦中看到了同一本书,
this time there was a string of pearls around it.
这次有个珍珠链围绕着它。
This psychic phase ended abruptly
这个心理阶段突然结束，
with a particularly clear picture episode in which
伴随着一个特别清晰的画面插曲，
I knew I had made an irrevocable choice.
我知道我已经做出了一个不可改变的选择。
I saw myself entering a cave
我看见自己走进一个洞穴，
cut into a rock formation on a bleak
这个洞穴是在一个荒凉的海风吹拂的
windswept sea coast.
海岸上凿开的岩层。
What I found in the cave
我在山洞里发现了
was a large and very old parchment scroll.
一张很大很古老的羊皮纸卷。
Its ends were attached to heavy gold tip poles
它的两端连接着沉重的黄金尖杆，
and the scroll was wrapped around them,
卷轴缠绕着它们的周围,
so that they met in the middle of the scroll
使它们在卷轴的中间贴合
and were tied tightly together.
并紧紧地绑在一起。
I managed to untie the ends and
我设法解开末端，
open the scroll just enough to reveal the center panel.
打开卷轴以露出中心面板。
On which two words were written.
上面写着两个字：
God is.
上主永恒如是。
Then I unrolled the scroll all the way and as I did so,
然后我一直展开卷轴,
tiny letters began to appear on
当我这样做的时候，
both sides of the panel.
面板两侧开始出现微小的字母。
The silent voice which I had heard before
我以前听到的那个静默之声
explained the situation mentally to me.
在心里向我解释了这个情况。
If you look at the left side
如果你看向左边，
you will be able to read the past
你就能看到过去，
said the voice,
那个声音说,
if you look at the right side
如果你看向右边，
you will be able to read the future,
你就能预知未来,
but I hesitated only a moment
但是在充分卷起卷轴
before rolling up the scrolls sufficiently
以隐藏除中心面板之外的所有内容之前，
to conceal everything except the centre panel.
我犹豫了一会儿。
I am not interested in reading the past or the future
我对了解过去和预知未来都不感兴趣，
I said with finality.
我肯定地说。
I will just stop with this.
我会就此打住。
The voice sounded both reassured and reassuring.
这个声音听起来既安心又可靠。
You made it that time, it said，Thank you!
祂说到，"这次你做到了，谢谢！"
And that it seemed was that.
看起来就是这样。
Helen prided herself as a research psychologist
海伦为自己是一个研究心理学家而自豪，
not as someone who heard voices who had
而不是一个在1965年整个夏天
heightened visual imagery
听到增强视觉影像
who experienced all of these psychic events
并经历过所有
that occurred throughout the summer of 1965.
这些通灵事件的人。
It was extremely distressing to her,
这对她来说是极大的痛苦,
she kept feeling that maybe she was losing her mind,
她一直觉得自己可能疯了,
certainly she couldn't reconcile all of this activity
当然她无法将所有这些活动与
with her scientific predilections.
她的科学偏好联系起来。
And this became a particularly acute problem for her
随着夏天和初秋的到来，
as the summer and early fall began.
这对她来说成了一个特别严重的问题。
One night she called me
一天晚上她打电话给我，
and this was in October and said you know that
那是在十月份，她说，
inner voice refuses to go away.
我内心的声音拒绝离开。
It keeps saying this is a course in miracles
它一直在说这是奇迹课程，
please take notes.
请记下笔记。
What shall I do
我该怎么办，
suppose it's crazy，suppose it doesn't make any sense,
如果这一切是疯狂的，如果这一切都毫无意义,
you know, suppose it's flipped.
如果它是颠倒的。
And she was obviously going through
那时她显然正经历着
a great deal of anguish and agony at that point.
巨大的痛苦和折磨。
But I said the only obvious thing
但我说了唯一显而易见的事，
Why don't you take down whatever it is,
"你为什么不把它记下来,
you can read it to me tomorrow morning in the office.
明天早上你可以在办公室读给我听。
And if it doesn't make any sense
如果它毫无意义，
no one else ever has to know about it,
其他人就不必知道它,
but at least we'll know what it is,
但至少我们知道它是什么。",
so that's what we did.
所以这就是我们所做的。
The next morning Helen came in
第二天早上，海伦走了进来，
and as she read that beautiful introduction to the text,
一边读着那篇优美的导言,里面说道，
which says， nothing real can be threatened,
"凡是真实的，不受任何威胁；
nothing unreal exists,
凡是不真实的，根本不存在；
herein lies the peace of god.
上主的平安即在其中。"
It was obvious that we were tuning in to something
我们很明显正在接收
that could hardly be regarded as crazy,
一些几乎会被视为疯狂的东西,
no matter how unexpected it was.
不管这是多么出乎意料。
A major contribution of miracles
"奇迹最大的功能在于
is their strength in releasing you
它有能力解除你
from your false sense of isolation
错误的孤立感、
deprivation and lack.
匮乏感即被剥削之感。"
A miracle is never lost.
"奇迹是永不失落的。
It may touch many people you have not even met.
它能够感动许多与你缘悭一面的人，
and produce undreamed of changes in situations
为远在天涯海角之人
of which you are not even aware.
带来不可思议的转变。"
Miracles are natural signs of forgiveness.
"奇迹是宽恕的自然结果。
Through miracles you accept god's forgiveness
奇迹表示你领受了上主的宽恕，
by extending it to others.
因为你已将宽恕推恩于人了。"
I would feel the writing coming on almost daily
我感觉几乎每天都在写作，
and sometimes several times a day,
有时一天要写好几次，
evenings turned out to be a favorite time for dictation.
晚上变成了我最喜欢的听写时间。
I objected bitterly to this
对此我很反感，
and often went to bed defiantly
常常带着挑衅的心情上床睡觉，
without writing anything,
什么也不写,
but I could not sleep,
但我睡不着,
eventually
最后，
I got up in some disgust and wrote as directed.
我厌恶地站起来，按照指示写了起来。
I never knew when I started a sentence how it would end
我从来不知道当我开始一个句子的时候，
and the ideas came
它会以什么样的方式结束，
so quickly that I had trouble keeping up with them.
想法来得如此之快，以至于我很难跟上它们。
Helen could turn it on or off at any time,
海伦可以随时打开或关闭听写通道,
she could stop in the middle of a sentence
她可以在句子说到一半的时候停下来
without even going back to reread what she had written
甚至不用重读她写的东西，
and continue when she had a moment she could
你可以在句子写到一半时开个研究会议
have a research conference
并在开完会之后继续，
in mid sentence it made no difference at all.
这对她来说根本没什么区别。
The flow of the material continued
材料的书写处于一种持续流动的状态，
without any altered state.
根本不会有任何改变。
Helen at no time was in a trance
海伦没有一刻处于恍惚状态，
or anything remotely resembling a trance.
也没有任何类似恍惚状态的东西。
But as I read the material,
但是当我阅读材料的时候,
I recognized that Helen in no way
我认识到海伦是
could have written this material, it was totally
不可能写出这样的材料，
alien to her background, to her interests and
这与她的背景、她的兴趣以及
her mode of conceptualizing abstract ideas that
她将抽象想法概念化的方式完全不同，
there's no way she could have done this.
她不可能做到这一点。
Where did the writing come from?
这些文字是从哪里来的？
I did not understand the come,
我不明白它们从何处来,
but impressive authority with which the voice dictated.
但是这个声音有着令人印象深刻的权威性。
It is largely because of the
很大程度上因为
strangely compelling nature of this authority
这种权威的奇怪的令人信服的性质，
that I have referred to the voice with a capital V.
我用一个大写V字来指代这个声音。
At several points in the writing,
在写作的几个点上,
the voice itself speaks in no uncertain terms
这个声音毫不含糊地
about the author Jesus.
提到作者——耶稣。
My own reactions to these references
我自己对这些参考文献
which literally stunned me at the time
的反应在当时简直
have decreased in intensity
让我大吃一惊，
and are now at a level of wonder and acceptance.
现在已经处于惊奇和接受的程度。
The name of Jesus Christ is such, is but a symbol
耶稣基督的名字是这样的，只是一个象征，
but it stands for love that is not of this world.
但它代表着不属于这个世界的爱。
This course comes from him
这门课来自于他，
because his words have reached you in a language
因为他的话已经用一种人们喜闻乐见和理解的
you can love and understand.
语言传达给了你。
The name of Jesus is the name of one who was a man
耶稣是一个人的名字，
but saw the face of Christ
他在他所有的弟兄中
in all his brothers and remembered God.
看到了基督的面容，并且忆起了上主。
Is he the Christ?
他是基督吗?
oh, yes.
哦，是的。
Along with you.
祂与你同行。
The first part of the material that we worked on
我们所写的材料的第一部分
lasted for almost three years
持续了将近三年，
and ended up as a 622 page volume.
最后写成了一本622页的书。
When the text was finished,
正文写完后,
Helen felt as I did that
海伦和我一样
that was the completion of our assignment.
认为我们的任务完成了。
And that we had plenty to do
我们还有很多事情要做，
to simply try to learn those concepts
只需简单地尝试学习这些概念，
and apply them in our lives.
并将它们应用到我们的生活中即可。
However after a period of perhaps nine months,
然而经过大约九个月的时间,
Helen got increasingly restless.
海伦变得越来越焦躁不安。
Then one day,
然后有一天,
she began to take down the workbook for students
她开始写下《学员练习手册》，
which consists of 365 lessons,
里面有365课，
one for each day of the year.
每天一节。
And that was the beginning of the second
这是课程
part of the course
第二部分的开始，
that took approximately two and a half years.
大约花了两年半的时间。
And at the end of that we
最后，我们又一次
again thought that we were finished.
认为我们已经完成了。
And after a number of months again of
又过了几个月，
not being quite sure of what would happen next,
不确定接下来会发生什么,
the 3rd and final volume was announced,
第三卷也是最后一卷
as the manual for teachers.
被宣布为《教师手册》。
So the total period of time
所以总的时间
was approximately seven years,
大约是七年,
from the time we began with the text,
从编写正文开始,
including the workbook and
包括学员练习手册，
finally the manual for teachers.
最后是教师手册。
I first met Helen,Bill in the fall of 1972
我第一次见到海伦和比尔是在1972年的秋天，
and then I swore the course for the first time
然后我在1973年5月
in May of 1973.
起誓研修课程。
And then after we spent a great deal of time together
我们在一起相处了很长时间，
and I think what impressed me first about Helen and Bill,
海伦和比尔给我的第一印象是,
I was despite all the conflict that
尽管他们彼此之间
they had with each other.
存在冲突，
and difficulties with the course of resistances to the course
并且在抵制课程的过程中遇到困难，
that was underlying a commitment that they both had made,
但他们都做出了这样的承诺，
to see that the purity of the course
即确保课程及其信息
and its message would never be changed,
的纯粹度永远不会改变,
and would always be main pure.
并保持永远是纯粹的。
And I think that always was extremely impressive to me.
我认为这让我印象非常深刻。
Helen and I spent a great deal of time together
海伦和我花了很多时间在一起，
we had dinner almost every night，
我们几乎每天晚上都一起吃晚饭，
she, her husband Louis and myself.
包括海伦、她的丈夫路易斯和我。
And we spend the great deal of time
我们花了大量的时间
going over the manuscript，
翻阅手稿，
making sure that its published form
确保其出版形式
it would be exactly the way Jesus wanted it.
完全符合耶稣所希望的。
And Helen herself was an extraordinary woman,
海伦本人是一位非凡的女性,
she would go from a moment of real other worldliness,
她会从一个真正的世俗时刻开始，
where her whole face would change
她的整张脸都会改变，
and she would tell me us
她会告诉我们，
that in those moments
在那些时刻，
she would look like beyond even Jesus,
她看起来甚至超越了耶稣,
beyond the relationship with them,
超越了与祂们的关系,
beyond hearing his voice,
超越了听到他的声音,
it was like being in the presence almost
仿佛置身于
of an ageless timeless wisdom.
不朽的永恒智慧中。
And then within seconds she go right back down
几秒钟后，她又回来了，
worrying about where her husband was
担心她丈夫在哪里，
how come he was waiting for supper
担心他怎么会等着吃晚饭，
and concerned about all Monday and things.
担心周一的事情。
I was teaching at New York University in 1975
1975年我在纽约大学教书，
and feeling full up with an exciting career
当时我在我们称之为
in what we then called experimental parapsychology
实验超心理学或意识研究的
or consciousness research,
令人兴奋的职业生涯中感到充实，
meeting very interesting people, traveling, speaking.
在旅行和演讲中结识非常有趣的人。
And I was feeling a sort of emptiness，
我感到一种空虚感，
I didn't know why?
我不知道为什么？
One night I locked myself in the bathroom in my home
一天晚上，我把自己锁在家里的浴室里，
and I went to pieces.
然后我就崩溃了。
I could say it was a form of surrender.
我可以说这是一种臣服。
I called out from the bottom of my heart
我从心底里呼唤，
want someone up there, please help me.
希望有人在那里，请帮帮我。
And I meant it.
我是认真的。
Within a very short time,
在很短的时间内,
I received the help I sought,
我得到了我所寻求的帮助,
but not in the form I anticipated.
但不是我预期的那种形式。
A few days after,
几天后,
I was asked by a good friend to accompany him to me to
我的一个好朋友邀请我陪他去
professor of medical psychology at Columbia University,
哥伦比亚大学内外科学院
school of physicians and surgeons.
医学心理学教授那里。
I went with him,
我和他一起去了,
not knowing what to expect or why the meeting,
我不知道会发生什么，也不知道为什么要开会,
but it seemed as if I was supposed to go.
但看起来好像我应该去。
And that kind of mood continued,
那种情绪还在继续,
as Bill took us inside the university
当比尔带我们进入大学，
where we had lunch
我们与比尔和
with Bill and his associate Helen Schucman.
他的同事海伦舒曼共进午餐。
I found her to be a very clever woman,
我发现她是一个非常聪明的女人，
very intellectual and well spoken,
智力超群，口才特好,
quite articulate and a bit sharp and I was intimidated.
口齿伶俐，有点尖刻，我当时被吓到了。
And the conversation was going in all different directions.
我们的谈话朝着不同的方向发展
And a little bit amused,
带着一点沉思,
I found myself turning to Helen
我转向海伦，
and saying to her,
对她说:
you're hearing an inner voice, aren't you?
"你听到了内心的声音，是吗？"。
And I didn't really know what I meant,
我不知道自己在说什么,
but she seemed quite startled.
但她看起来很吃惊。
And she said, I beg your pardon.
她说: "请再说一遍。"
And Bill try to sue the situation, he said, well
比尔试图缓解这种情况，他说，
Helen, let's go back to our office and
"海伦，我们回办公室
let's talk about this in private.
私下谈谈。"
And the two of them took me back to their office
他们两个把我带回他们的办公室，
and closed the door.
并关上了门。
And she handed me the text, with its introduction
她递给我正文，还有正文的导言，
and I took it from her,
我从她那里拿过来,
and I put it on my lap.
把它放在膝盖上。
As the others were talking among themselves
当其他人在彼此交谈时，
and I looked down at it,
我低头看着它,
I opened up the black binder
我打开黑色的活页夹，
and I turned to the introduction
翻开导言，我读到:
and I read, this is a course in miracles,
"这是阐释奇迹的课程，
it's a required course
是一门必修的课程。"
and there was no question in my mind
我心中毫无疑问，
that I was being given a miracle.
我被赐予了一个奇迹。
And that I had asked for it.
而这正是我所请求的。
In New York, Judith Skutch Whitson
在纽约，朱迪思·斯库奇·惠特森
spent a great deal of time with Helen Schucman
花了大量时间与海伦·舒曼在一起，
and she quickly recognized the profound
她很快意识到了
importance of the course.
这门课程的深远意义。
This became a turning point in Judith's life
这成为朱迪思人生的转折点，
and she soon helped establish the Nonprofit
她很快帮忙建立了
Foundation for Inner Peace
心灵平安基金会，
and found a way to publish the course.
并找到了出版这门课程的方法。
Tolerance for pain may be high,
"人忍受痛苦的耐力虽高,
but it is not without limit.
终究有其限度。
Eventually everyone begins to recognize
迟早，心灵会隐隐地冒出一念，
however dimly that there must be a better way.
一定还有更好的途径才对。
As this recognition becomes more firmly established,
当这一体会愈来愈根深蒂固时，
it becomes a turning point.
便成了人生的转折点,
This ultimately reawakens spiritual vision.
这一念终将唤醒人的灵心慧眼。"
A Course In Miracles has helped many make new choices in their live.
奇迹课程帮助许多人在其生活中作出新的选择
I can't even imagine what my life would have been,
如果我没有找到奇迹课程，
if I had not found a course in miracle.
我甚至无法想象我的生活会是什么样子。
When I first picked it up at my apartment,
当我第一次在公寓里拿到书时,
I started reading it voraciously,
我开始如饥似渴地阅读,
then it was really time for me.
对我来说是时候了。
And I felt as so many people said
正如很多人所说的，
that I had come home.
我觉得我回家了。
What I did have that a course in miracles gave me
奇迹课程给了我
is a deep sense that
一种深刻的感觉，
faith in God is inseparable from
即对上主的信仰是与
faith in other people.
对其他人的信仰密不可分。
And that's what it means to me in my life it is
这就是它在我生命中的意义，
a continuous reminder,
它不断地提醒着我,
that my temptation to find guilt in my brother
我试图在我兄弟身上找罪咎
is an attack on myself,
是对我自己的攻击,
that was what so moves me the first day
这就是第一天读到
I ever read a page of the course in miracles.
奇迹课程让我很感动的原因。
And it's the message that most moves me today.
这是如今最让我感动的内容。
Trials are but lessons that you fail to learn
"考验不过是你过去
presented once again,
尚未学会的人生课题再度出现于你眼前,
so where you made a faulty choice before
让你在过去选错之处
you now can make a better one,
作出更好的选择,
and thus escape all pain
摆脱过往错误
that what you chose before has brought to you.
带给你的痛苦。"
In every difficulty, all distress and each perplexity
在每一个困难，在所有的苦恼和困惑中，
Christ calls to you and gently says,
基督呼唤着你，温柔地说:
"My brother,
"我的兄弟,
choose again."
重新选择吧！"
As an actor, I've played many roles in my career,
作为演员，我在演艺生涯中扮演过许多角色,
but in my life I've only played one
但我这辈子只扮演过一个角色，
which is the victim.
那就是受害者。
I'm always victimized by something or someone,
我总是被某些事或某些人所害,
so I decided to look for a way out
所以我决定寻找出路
and an explanation to all this.
和对这一切的解释。
I picked up about every possible
我从灵性书店里挑选了
path and technique from the spiritual supermarket
所有可能的方法和技巧的资料，
and nothing worked.
但都没有任何效果。
So six years ago
六年前，
the course was translated into Spanish
这门课被翻译成西班牙语，
and I picked it up and started a little bit.
我便开始学了起来。
And I knew there was something there
我知道这门课
the course would teach me
会教我一些东西，
that victimization feelings are not a fact
受害感并不是事实，
but an interpretation you're putting to them.
而是你对它们的解释。
But what is more important,
但更重要的是,
it would teach me I have a presence of love within me.
它教会我明白我心中有爱的存在。
I can call for help
我可以寻求帮助，
which I did and nowadays I experience a very
现在我经历了一个
strong presence of love next to me.
非常强烈的爱的临在。
Whenever I feel victimized by something or someone,
每当我觉得被某事或某人伤害时,
I can call for help.
我可以请求帮助。
And he teaches me
他告诉我
it's not an attack.
这不是攻击。
But just the silly things we do to each other
但是当我们害怕时候，我们都很害怕时，
when we are afraid, we are all afraid.
我们会彼此做一些愚蠢的事情。
And that has changed my life,
这改变了我的生活，
because now I am not desperate or alone anymore.
因为现在我不再感到绝望或孤独。
And I feel a deep sense of peace that
我感到一种深深的平安感，
nothing ever gave me before.
这是以前没有任何东西给过我的。
All my life
在我的一生中，
I've always felt a sense of emptiness and alienation
我总是感到空虚和疏离，
and I never really understood it because
而我从来没有真正理解过它们，
I've always been somewhat
因为我总在
successful in terms of the world.
这个世界上取得某种成功。
And I tried to fill up this sense of emptiness
我试图通过课程，
through courses, through civil rights and
通过公民权利和参与和平运动来
in the peace movement.
填补这种空虚感。
I was lived in an African the peace corps for two years
我在一个非洲和平组织住了两年，
and then I got a PHD and I traveled all over the world.
然后我拿到了博士学位并周游世界。
And each one of these experiences
这些经历中的每一个
actually was a disappointment
实际上都令人失望的，
because it just didn't do what
因为它没有达到
I thought it would do for me.
我想象中的效果。
About nine years ago,
大约九年前，
I was working with people with aids
我和艾滋病患者一起工作，
and I loved the work was very challenging and intense.
我喜欢这份充满挑战和强度的工作。
But one day I began to realize that
但是有一天我开始意识到
I couldn't continue giving hope to my clients,
我不能继续给我的客户带来希望，
because I felt hopeless myself.
因为我自己感到绝望。
And I just said, there must be a better way.
于是我说，一定有更好的方法。
Soon after that I found a course of miracles and
不久之后，我发现了奇迹课程，
it wasn't at all what I thought it would be,
它完全不是我想象的那样,
but it really taught me that
但它真的教会了我，
I do have an inner teacher inside me
那就是我的内心深处确实有一位老师。
And I don't have to go to things outside
我不用去外面找东西
to fill that need in that emptiness
来填补那份空虚的需要，
and I don't have to use people to meet my needs.
我也无需利用他人来满足我的需求。
I've also seen that relationships with
我也看到了
people in my family and my friends and
我与家人和朋友的关系
my whole purpose toward work
以及我作为大学教授工作的
which is a university professor has changed
全部目的都发生了变化，
because all of these are used as a classroom to get closer
因为所有这些都是用作道场来
to the love of God.
让我更靠近上主的爱。
I think that the most
我认为这门课程
important thing the course has taught me
教会我的最重要的事情是，
is that I no longer have a sense of hopelessness.
我不再有绝望感。
I see in my own life a tremendous growth
我在自己的生活中看到了巨大的成长，
especially over the last few years
尤其是在过去的几年里，
as I've been studying the course in miracles,
我一直在研究这门奇迹课程,
that I've come to a point
我已经到了这样一个地步，
that I am at least able to see
即我至少可以看到
the baggage I'm dragging behind me
拖我人生后腿的是什么,
and realizing that it's my choice to release that
并意识到释放它是我的选择。
And in releasing those illusions
在释放那些幻觉的过程中，
and they are illusions because the past is over,
它们都是幻觉，因为过去的已经结束了，
it can touch us not,
它无法触及我们,
and the future is not,
未来也一样，
nothing exists,
什么都不存在,
but the present now, this holy instant now.
只有当下，神圣的此刻。
And once one gets that,
一旦人们领会了这一点,
there is just tremendous power,
就会有巨大的力量,
because there,
因为在那里,
you are defenseless,
你无需防备,
there is no need to feel vulnerable to the world
你不需要感到自己在
that you're joined with.
这个世界上很脆弱。
And it's a wonderful healing process
这是一个美妙的疗愈过程，
and I think when we mirror that to each other,
我认为当我们彼此映射时,
it's non stoppable.
它是不可阻挡的。
Part of my work as a clinician in this county was
作为这个县的临床医生，我的一部分工作
consulting with oncologist with children who
是对患有非常严重疾病并且
had very serious illness and were dying.
濒临死亡的小孩进行治疗的肿瘤科医生。
And I noted that
我注意到很多
many of these children oftentimes ask the doctor or nurse
这样的孩子经常问医生或者护士，
this is way back now in 1975,
那是1975年的事了,
about their thoughts, about dying and their fears about dying
他们会问关于死亡以及对死亡的恐惧的想法。
And oftentimes the nurse and the doctor would just change the subject.
通常护士和医生会转移话题。
And occurred to me there need to be a place where
我突然意识到孩子们
kids could really talk and
需要一个能畅所欲言
have an honest reaction
并得到诚实回应的地方，
because oftentimes the same kids would find
因为很多时候这批孩子会发现
the person who was the most
最诚实的人
honest was the woman who was scrubbing the floor
是那个擦地板的女人，
and she would give an honest response.
因为她会给出诚实的回答。
And I gave a lecture back in New York
我在纽约做了一个关于
on the prevention of cancer
预防癌症的演讲，
and talking about some of the things
并在一对一的基础上
I was doing on a one to one basis,
讨论了一些我正在做的一些
really utilizing course principles.
真正利用课程原则的事情。
And what occurred to me was I was to start
我想到我要开始这件事，
it was like my meditation on the plane coming back
就像我在回来的飞机上所做的冥想，
I was to start a center that would make use
在这个冥想中，我建立了一个中心，
of the course principles that allow me to look at
该中心利用课程原则让我能够
death differently.
以不同的方式看待死亡。
And really the children would teach me
孩子们真的教会了我
these spiritual principles.
这些灵性原则。
And I was just to be the catalyst for setting it up
我只是作为设置它的催化剂，
and I set it up really based on the course principles,
我根据课程原则设置了它,
not saying to children, look,
而不是对孩子们说，看啊,
I have a better way of
我有比别人
dealing with this than someone else,
更好的处理方法,
but I'd like your help,
而是说，我需要你的帮助,
can we be colleagues with each other
我们相互能成为伙伴，
about a different way of looking at the world.
以不同的目光看待这个世界。
And maybe it would be possible
也许这是可能的,
if you got together with other children
如果你和其他孩子在一起，
and could talk with them about their problems,
并且可以和谈论他们的问题，
you could end up helping
你最终可能比
each other far better than doctors and nurses and teachers.
医生、护士和老师更好地互相帮助。
And so we start in that way,
所以我们就这样开始,
the Center for Attitudinal Healing actually makes use of
态度治愈中心实际上利用了
many of the principles of the course of miracles,
许多奇迹课程的原则,
because what is attitude in the healing
因为在治疗中我们的态度是
except letting go of the negative thoughts of fear
除了放下恐惧、愤怒的
and anger and attack thoughts,
消极思想和攻击思想，
and having them replace with love,
更重要的是用爱取而代之,
that's always been there.
因为爱一直都在那里。
So this is what we attitude in healing is all about.
这就是我们在治疗中的态度。
I began going around talking about love and God,
我开始到处谈论爱和上主,
some things that we don't talk about medical school.
这些都是医学院不讨论的一些事情。
The majority of doctors,
大多数医生，
they became very skeptical, very concerned, very wondrous,
他们变得非常怀疑，非常关心，非常好奇,
but what happened
但发生的事情是，
was that the families that we were seeing,
我们看到的那些家庭,
children who had catastrophic illness that
他们的孩子患有灾难性的疾病，
there was such rapid shifts in their feelings,
他们的情绪变化如此之快,
their whole family structure had changed so rapidly
整个家庭结构发生了如此迅速的变化，
that these very physicians that were very skeptical began
以至于这些非常怀疑的医生
to refer people to us.
开始将人们转介给我们。
And one thing's been helpful
在这门课程中，
most accord from the course it says,
有一点很有帮助，那就是，
I'm not a body.
"我不是一具身体。
I am free
我是自由的，
For I'm still as God created me.
因为我仍是上主所创造的我。"
The peace of God is everything I want.
"我只要上主的平安。
The peace of God is my one goal;
上主的平安是我唯一的目标，
the aim of all my living here, the end I seek,
是我活在世上的目的，亦是我追寻的终点；
my purpose and my function and my life,
它是我流落异乡的一切目的、一切任务与
while I abide where I'm not at home.
生命之所寄。"
And showed them that the center had really been
向他们展示了这个中心对我来说，
greatly helpful to me at taking
真的是非常有帮助，
another look at the body
它让我重新审视了身体，
and seeing the difference between life and death.
并看到了生与死之间的区别。
One child who had sickle cell anemia named Carrie,
有个孩子得了镰刀型红血球疾病，他的名字是凯立，
I was asking him,
我问他,
what do you thought about death?
"你对死亡有什么看法?"。
He'd come close to death many times,
他多次濒临死亡,
he said, well, Jerry,
他说，"杰瑞,
I think what happens when you die
我认为，当你死后发生的事情是，
is that God has really created a library
上主创造了一个图书馆，
and you're a book in this library and what he does
而你是这个图书馆里的一本书，
is he just loans this book to your parents.
他所做的只是把这本书借给你的父母。
And it's on a long basis and when the due date is up
这个租借期很长，当截止日期到的时候，
that book comes back into God's heart,
这本书就会重新回到上主的心中,
so you're never really separate from God
所以你永远不会真正与上主分离，
and when your time's up you just go home,
当时间到了，你就回家了，
to the heart of God.
回到上主的心中。"
And I thought, wow，what a beautiful way of looking at it.
我想，哇，这是一种多么美妙的看待方式。
I came to UC Virgil around 1967
1967年左右，我来到加州大学维吉尔分校，
in the very turbulent years at the school,
当时学校里动荡不安，
a lot of racial strife.
种族冲突频发。
And around 1968 1969,
大约在1968-1969年间,
I took a lot of courses, a lot of courses,
我上了很多很多课，
sociology,psychology, political science.
有社会学、心理学以及政治学。
And every the theme in all of these was
所有这些课程的主题都是
lifes were poor， lifes were deprived
生命是可伶的，生命被剥夺了，
lifes were the vegeta of society.
生命是社会的草芥。
Are we going to look at
我们要带着
the society with anger and frustration?
愤怒和沮丧来看待这个社会吗？
And around at the same time,
与此同时,
there was a group of people
有一群人自称
call themselves a nation of Islam
来自伊斯兰国家，
and it basically taught like supremacy.
他们的教义基本上是至高无上的。
And I lived this adoption I ate it, I slept.
我在这种教养中长大，并无知无觉。
I didn't really socialize for fights for seven years
我有七年没有参加社交活动了，
so I went over to JFK and I was like, you know
于是我去了肯尼迪国际机场，我很喜欢那里，
this is the very first I hadn't been on the campus
这是我第一次不在校园里，
or in a white environment for seven years.
也不在我待了七年的白人环境里。
It was a lady there named Judith Skutch,
在那里有一位名叫朱迪思·斯卡奇的女士，
she was introducing a set of books title,a course in miracles.
她正在介绍一套书，名字叫《奇迹课程》。
And when Judith read this introduction,
当朱迪思读到导言时,
I had this experience
我有了一种
that I hadn't experienced since I was a child,
从小以来就没有过的体验,
I was one with everything in the room,
我与房间里的一切融为一体，
I felt totally at peace.
我感到完全的平安。
And something deep inside of me said,
我内心深处有个声音说,
"This is a tool for you,use it."
"这是你的一个工具，好好利用它吧。"
When I first read a course of miracles,
当我第一次读到奇迹课程时,
the ideas that our home is in God's presence,
认为我们的家就在上主面前,
that we are spirit and not the body,
我们是灵性而不是肉体,
that we have been created
我们被创造为
as one with each other and our source.
和彼此以及源头合一的一体。
I just knew it was true.
我就知道这是真的。
I'd had the experience.
我有过这样的经历。
I didn't need validation of the experience
我不需要经验的验证
to know it was true,
就知道这是真的,
but I did need an intellectual system to help me apply it.
但我确实需要一个知识体系来帮助我应用它。
And that's what I first noticed about the course
这就是我第一次注意到这门课程，
that I could start with a lesson a day
我可以从每天一节课开始，
to start to unlearn
开始忘记那些
the mistakes that have been programmed into my mind.
已经植入我脑子里的错误思想。
That I could remember more clearly
我可以更清楚地忆起，
that indeed I am spirit
我就是灵性。
And in that sense, I'm at home
从这个意义上来说，我在家里，
and totally safe.
并且完全安全。
I don't have to go any place to find safety.
我不需要去任何地方寻找安全感。
I don't have to be anyone different.
我不必成为任何与众不同的人。
I just have to remember who I am.
我只需要记住我是谁。
Nothing outside change, but what's inside I began to change,
外面的一切都没有改变，但内在的我开始改变,
I began to see the love
我开始看到
that was there between from human to human.
存在于人与人之间的爱。
I began to experience
我开始去体验，
that I began to get new friends who were not
我开始去结交一些
look that didn't just look like me,
与我长得不一样的新朋友，
who were white, you know,
一些是白人,
who were Hispanic or you know,
一些是西班牙裔，
the color became, was not an issue.
肤色不再是个问题。
In my relationships,
在我的关系中，
I began to see that
我开始认识到
all men are created equal
人人生而平等，
unless we see that，
除非我们看到到这一点，
we're not gonna experience peace.
不然我们不会体验到平安。
I begin to see that，um
我开始认识到，
anytime I see myself has been above another human being
无论何时，只要我看到自己凌驾于他人之上，
or below a human being
或者屈服于他人之下，
I'm not gonna experience peace.
我就不会体验到平安。
Two of my favorite quotes from the course are two lessons.
课程中我最喜欢的两句话是在两节课中。
Number one, thirty four，which is
第一句话是来自，第34课（实际上在第135课），
"If I defend myself I am attacked."
"自我自卫表示我受到了攻击"。
And the other is one eighty five or two eighty five，which is,
另一句话是是第185课或第285课（实际上是在第284课），
my mind can change all thoughts that hurt.
"我的思想可以改变一切有害念头"。
These I have found
这些是我找到的
a tremendous practical value in going through life
在生活中有着巨大实用价值的正见。
And I've also found that
另外我还发现
in dealing with other people
在与其他人打交道时，
and especially when we go into the prisons
尤其是当我们进入监狱
and deal with people who are in prison,
并与监狱中的人打交道时，
that these two lessons are very pragmatic,
这两句话是非常务实的,
very practical
非常实用，
and are tremendous value to those people
对于那些发现自己陷入困境的人来说，
who have found themselves in that situation.
是非常有价值的。
The course started letting me get peace,
课程开始让我得到平安,
letting me relax.
让我放松。
And I started experimenting
然后我开始尝试
with the lessons that I was picking up and
应用我学到的课程，
trying to mount on people.
并尝试在人们身上应用。
And I started getting real warmth and closeness.
我开始感受到真正的温暖和亲密感。
And in touch with people
与人接触的过程中，
when they heard I hurt
当他们听到我的伤害时，
not out of sympathy but out of empathy,
不是出于同情，而是出于同理心，
I could understand more clearly
在经历过痛苦和
having experienced the pain and
堕落以及在监狱中发生的事情后
the degradations and the things that go on in prison.
我可以更清楚地理解这些事情，
and not pointing fingers that that's their fault
而不是指责那是他们的错，
they did that to me，society did that to me,
他们这样对我，社会那样对我,
the jury did that to me.
陪审团这样对我。
The judge that I thought was real clear now that
我认为法官现在已经很清楚了，
and I did that to me.
那是我自作自受。
And I allowed myself to become unconnected,
我让自己变得孤立无援,
I allowed myself to be unloving and unavailable
我允许自己变得没有爱心、不可用、
and resentful and bitter and things like that.
充满怨恨和痛苦等等。
Once I got that then it was real clear that
一旦我明白了这一点，
it was okay to tell somebody that
我就可以很清楚地告诉别人，
what I love you and be in prison at the same time.
我爱你，在监狱里也是可以的。
What the course does for a lot of people
该课程对很多人的作用是
is to get them to know recognize almost instantly
让他们几乎在瞬间认识到，
that they are not acting the way they want
他们的行为不是他们想要的，
and they can change their minds,
他们可以改变他们的想法，
because they are aware of that.
因为他们意识到了这一点。
And that is as much of a help as anything
这对你的帮助不亚于任何事情，
because it stops you from going in a direction
因为它能阻止你走向一个
that you inherently really don't want to do,
你实际上并不想去的方向，
you don't want to be conflicted,
你不希望有冲突，
nobody wants to be conflicted,
没有人想要冲突,
they want to be loving and they want to love.
他们想成为有爱的人，他们想要去爱。
And if it stops you from being conflicted,
而如果这能阻止你的冲突，
which is what it does for
这也是它对很多学习
a lot of people who study this course.
这门课程的人所起的作用。
A lot of the courses about
很多关于以不同的方式
living in the world in a different way,
生活在世界上的课程,
also a lot of it's about guilt,
也有很多是关于罪咎的,
two of the things obviously that caused the
有两个东西明显引起了
greatest degree of guilt
最大程度的罪咎，
and all of us here are sex and money.
那就所有人都有的，即性和金钱。
And while the course takes positions on nothing,
虽然这门课没有什么立场,
the course is not a system of behavior,
它不是一个行为系统,
the course is a system in mind changing,
但它是一个思想改变的系统,
really I think what it
我真的认为
has taught me regarding those two subjects is
它教给了我性和金钱
that sex and money are neutral things,
这两个主题其实是中性的东西,
in which I invest my meaning.
我在其中赋予我自己的意义。
Like everything else in the world,
就像世界上的其他事物一样,
the body, the world itself, sex, money,
身体、世界本身、性、金钱,
whatever else it would happen to be,
不管发生了什么,
each thing only has the meaning that my mind gives it.
每件事都只有我的想法赋予它的意义。
If I make sex a very important thing to me
如果我把性爱当做一件非常重要的事情
and make it something that I need,
并且让它成为我需要的东西,
I'm giving power to sex that sex doesn't have.
我就赋予了性所没有的力量。
If I make money something very important to me
如果我花了大半辈子的时间
which I did for a good portion of my life,
赚到了对我来说很重要的钱,
then I make money something
那么我就让钱成为
that is that it really isn't.
它所不是的东西。
And I think the easiest way to say it is this,
我觉得最简单的说法就是,
the course of miracles teaches you,
奇迹课程教会你,
to live in the moment.
活在当下。
In order to live in the moment,
为了活在当下,
you have to do a couple things,
你得做几件事,
you must forgive,
你必须宽恕,
so that you can trust.
这样你才能信任。
You must have no defenses,
你必须毫无防备，
so you don't feel that you're going to be attacked,
这样你才不会觉得自己会受到攻击,
but assuming that you can go through the sequence of no defenses,
但是假设你可以经历一系列没有防备的过程，
forgiveness of your brother
宽恕你的弟兄
for what he didn't do to you
并没有对你做的事情，
and then trust and you can live in the moment.
然后相信他，你就可以活在当下。
Then all those things become meaningless,
然后所有这些都变得毫无意义,
money becomes meaningless,
金钱变得毫无意义,
because living in the moment is the whole point.
因为活在当下才是最重要的。
Money is a future oriented thing.
金钱是一种面向未来的东西。
Sex becomes something that you do or you don't do it,
性成为你可做或可不做的事情。
if it's there and you should do it，you do it,
如果它在那里，你觉得应该做，那你就做；
if you do it's not there and you don't
如果你做，它不在那里，你觉得不做，
you don't do it,
那你就不做。
it doesn't become
它不会变成比
something that's more important than it should be.
它本应该更重要的东西。
And unfortunately for us,
对我们来说不幸的是,
way back for the story of Genesis on through the world,
追溯到创世纪的故事,
sex has become something that's almost like the serpent,
性已经成为一种几乎像蛇一样的东西,
we should hate the serpent,
我们应该憎恨蛇,
we should hate sex.
我们应该讨厌做爱。
We should feel guilty when we have sex,
我们做爱的时候应该感到罪咎;
we should feel guilty if we have too much money,
如果我们有太多的钱，我们应该感到罪咎;
we should feel guilty if we have too little money,
如果我们的钱太少，我们应该感到罪咎;
That's kind of absurd.
这有点荒谬。
So I think what the course has taught me to do
我认为这门课程教会我要做的就是
is to take one step back from those emotion ridden things
从那些充满情绪的事情中退后一步,
and recognize that the emotion that's in there,
并且认识到那里面的情绪,
I put in there,
是我投放进去的,
and I can subtract it out.
而我也可以消除它。
And then in doing so I can see it in balance.
然后在这样做的时候，我可以看到它的平衡。
And I think if there's anything that the course
而且我认为，如果要说在很长一段时间
would teach us over a long period of time
这门课教会我的是什么的话，
is to become in balance.
那就是中道。
I encountered a course in miracles at
在我生命中一个非常关键的时刻，
a very critical time in my life when
我遇到了奇迹课程
I was chief of the Foreign Affairs
当时我是
in National Defense Division
国会图书馆国防部
of the Library of Congress.
外交事务处处长。
And had 150
有150名专业人士
professional men and women working for me and for
为我和国会工作，
the congress to clarify major issues of
以澄清国防政策和外交政策
defense policy and foreign policy.
的重大问题。
And it was a very rich and full life,
而这是一个非常丰富和充实的生活，
a very useful career you might say,
你可以说是一个非常有用的职业生涯，
as far as informing congress about the
因为它让国会了解到
different ways of looking at foreign and defense policy issues.
看待外交和国防政策问题的不同方式。
But unfortunately at precisely the time when
但不幸的是，
from an outsider's perception of me,
恰恰在外人看来，
my life seemed to be most useful,
我的人生似乎处在最风生水起
it had the least meaning.
但又最没有意义的时候。
Several quotations became my guide and I guess
书中的几句引文成了我的向导，
in a sense the one that was most startling for me
我想从某种意义上来说，最让我吃惊的是
was the quotation
这句引文：
"do not seek to change the world,
“不要试图改变世界,
instead change your mind about it".
而是要改变对它的看法”。
Now given the fact that my entire professional life
鉴于我的整个职业生涯是
had been dedicated to leaving the world a better place
致力于让世界变得更美好，
in effect of changing some of the things
从而改变我认为世界上
that I thought were wrong with the world.
有问题的一些事情。
And my technique for doing that was to try to understand
我做的方式是尝试通过理解
economics, politics, strategy,
经济学、政治学、战略学、
psychology, sociology, the Chinese language.
心理学、社会学以及中文。
I had a great deal of education that
我接受了大量旨在变得
aimed at being more useful.
更有用的教育。
And yet as time went on,
但随着时间的推移，
I became very clear that as they say in Washington
我变得非常清楚，正如他们在华盛顿所说，
where I stand on an issue depends on where I sit.
我在一个问题上的立场取决于我站在何处。
So when I read this first quote in the course,
当我在课程中读到这第一句话时，
it was something that people say in California
这是人们在加州说的一些话，
really resonated with me.
引起了我深深的共鸣。
It sounded true.
它听起来很真实。
The journey to God
"迈向上主的旅程
is merely the reawakening
不过是再次觉醒于
of the knowledge of where you are always，
你的本来境界以及
and what you are forever.
你的永恒真相而已。
It is a journey without distance
那是当下即至的旅程，
to a goal that has never changed.
目标永远不变。"
You dwell not here,
"你不住在这里，
but in eternity.
而是活在永恒里。
You travel but in dreams,
你只是在梦中流浪，
while safe at home.
其实你安居家中。"
The Spiritual Teachings of A Course in Miracles
奇迹课程的灵性教导
I think it is the vision of universal innocence
我认为是普世纯洁无罪的愿景
that makes the course in miracles
使奇迹课程吸引了
attract so many people.
如此众多的人。
That's not an easy spirituality by the way，
顺便说一句，这不是一个容易的灵性之旅，
it's not an easy spirituality at all.
这根本不是一个容易的灵性之旅。
It merely is a message
它仅仅是这样一个信息，
that until and unless we are willing to see
即除非我们愿意看到
the innocence in others and ourselves，
他人和自己的纯洁无罪，
we cannot experience the peace of God.
否则我们无法体验到上主的平安。
The course of miracle says that heaven
奇迹课程告诉我们，
is not a conditional place
天堂不是需要某种条件才能进入之域，
but an awareness of our oneness.
而是对我们的一体性的觉知。
And we are one in our innocence,
我们是纯洁无罪的一体生命,
obviously the way that we air,
只是我们的表达方式不同,
the ways that we make mistakes are different.
我们的犯错方式不同。
Your mistakes are different than my mistakes,
你我的错误虽不同,
but your innocence is the same as my innocence.
但你我一样都是纯洁无罪的。
You have but two emotions, love and fear.
"你只有两种情感，即爱和恐惧。
One you made and one was given you.
一种是你自己营造的，另一种是上天所赐的。
Each is a way of seeing
每一种情感不过代表一种看的角度，
and different worlds arise from their different sights.
不同的眼光也会架构出不同的世界"。
See the love of God in you
"仅仅瞩目于你心内的上主之爱吧，
and you will see it everywhere,
你随时随地都能看到它的，
because it is everywhere.
因为那爱确实无处不在"。
With love in you,
"这爱就在你内，
you have no need except to extend it.
你只有一个需求，就是把爱推恩出去"。
The course is predicated on two belief systems.
本课程以两个信念系统为基础。
One is real the other is false.
一个为真，另一个为假。
The false belief system is one the ego adheres to.
错误信念系统是自我所坚持的。
And that is,
这个错误信念就是,
that we're born into this world in physical bodies,
我们以肉体出生于这个世界,
in a world that is real, the physical.
生活在一个真实的世界，一个物理的世界。
And things happen to us
而事情发生在我们身上，
and sometimes we experience happiness,
有时我们体验到幸福,
once in a while, joy,
偶尔有些欢乐，
very often, depression and anxiety
常常抑郁和焦虑，
certainly disease and always death.
肯定会生病，而且不免一死。
And that's the system of thought that the ego loves,
而这就是自我所喜爱的、
the ego adheres to, the ego exalts
自我所坚持的和推崇的、
and the ego wants us to believe in.
自我想让我们相信的思想体系。
On the other hand
另一方面，
there's a belief system
还有一种信念体系认为
that God is our reality,
上主就是我们的现实,
we are created in God's image as spirit,
我们是按照上主的形象创造出来的灵性,
not the physical body,
而不是肉体,
that we are love,
我们是爱,
that a property of love is light.
爱的本质是光。
And that we are eternal,
我们是永恒的,
we cannot be hurt or inviolate,
我们不可能受到伤害或侵犯，
we can't be destroyed.
我们不可能被毁灭。
When one puts it that way,
如果有人这么说的话,
who but an insane person would want to choose the ego.
只有疯子才会选择自我。
One of the things I've learned from working with
我从与客户的心理治疗工作中
clients in psychotherapy is that
学到的一件事是，
they tend to get better
当他们对自己的经历负责时，
when they take responsibility for their experience.
他们往往会变得更好。
And the course speaks to this very directly,
课程非常直接地说明了这一点,
it says simply, I am responsible for what I see.
简单地说，我要对我所看到的负责。
I choose the feelings that I experience
我选择我所经历的感受，
and I decide upon the goal I would achieve.
而我决定了我要实现的目标。
And everything that seems to happen to me
而一切似乎发生在我身上的事情，
I ask for and receive as I have asked.
我都会按照我的要求来请求和接受。
Now that's quite a challenge
现在，如果我们要从表面上接受这一点的话，
if we're going to accept that at face value,
那将是一个相当大的挑战,
but in fact it gives us a sense of direction,
但实际上它给了我们一种方向感,
it points out to us that we need to take responsibility
它向我们指出我们需要
for the feelings we have.
为自己的感受负责。
And that if I'm angry,
如果我生气了,
at some level that's a choice
在某种程度上，这是一个选择，
it may be out of defensiveness,
它可能是出于防御,
it may be out of fear.
也许是出于恐惧。
But that basically I can choose whether I want to
但基本上我可以选择是否
release that anger to work it through,
通过释放愤怒来解决这个问题,
and move on or whether I want to
然后继续前进，或者，
remain stuck in it, so to speak.
我是否还想继续困在其中。
And I think that sometimes a problem
我认为有时候问题是，
because in psychotherapy
因为在心理治疗中，
we often emphasize the importance of expressing anger,
我们经常强调表达愤怒的重要性,
but we forget that that's not an endpoint
但我们忘记了，当一个人觉得自己
when a person feels like a victim,
是受害者时，这并不是一个终点,
it may be very appropriate for them to get angry about it,
他们为此生气可能非常合适,
but it's also appropriate for them to release that
但他们也应该释放出来，
and to move on.
然后继续前进。
So that in order to get in touch with our creativity,
为了发挥我们的创造力,
to be truly creative rather than reactive in our lives,
在我们的生活中要真正有创造力而不是被动反应,
we need to get beyond the position of victim and
我们需要超越受害者的立场，
the position of adversary and angry, reactivity
超越对手、愤怒和反应的立场进入
into a more creative view of
在我们生活中可能发生的
what's possible in our lives.
更有创造性的视角。
You may believe
"你也许还认为，
that you are responsible for what you do
你只需对你自己的言行负责，
but not for what you think.
而不必对你的想法负责。
The truth is
事实是，
that you are responsible for what you think
你只能对你的想法负责，
because it is only at this level
因为只有在这一层次上，
that you can exercise choice.
你才能选择的余地。
What you do comes from what you think.
你的行为乃是出自你的想法。"
Do not try to look beyond yourself for truth.
"千万不要向外寻找真相，
For truth can only be within you.
真相只可能存于你内。"
My interest in the course of miracles
我对奇迹课程的兴趣
began some years ago when
始于几年前，
I was doing research at the university of California
当时我在加利福尼亚大学做
on meditation and different schools of religion.
关于冥想和不同宗教流派的研究。
And someone showed me a copy of the course
有人给我看了这门课程的复印件，
and I reacted with great skepticism and
我的反应是极大的怀疑，
refused to look at it for a couple of years
几年来我一直拒绝去看它，
until when I finally did I was quite surprised.
直到我终于看时，我才感到十分惊讶。
And surprisingly impressed, particularly by two things:
令我惊讶的并留下深刻印象的是两件事：
one was that I found there was a psychological system
其一是我发现里面有一个
within it which was very sophisticated
非常复杂的心理系统，
and on a power in many ways with
在许多方面与当代
some contemporary thinking in western psychology;
西方心理学的一些思想有相同的力量。
and the second thing that
其二，
surprised and impressed me was that it
令我惊讶和印象深刻的是，
became clear that this
很明显，
seemed to represent an example of the
这似乎代表了
underlying perennial wisdom which
一个潜在的长青哲学的例子，
seems to lie at the core of the world's great religions.
这似乎是世界上最伟大宗教的核心。
The course was intended for self study
这个课程是为自学而设的，
and it has been translated into many
基金会已将其翻译成
languages by the foundation.
多种语言。
But it is here，in Roscoe, New York,
这里是纽约市罗斯科，
at the foundation for a course in miracles,
在奇迹课程基金会,
that co-founders Kenneth and Gloria Wapnick,
共同创始人肯尼斯和格洛丽亚
offer classes for students
为渴望深入这个课程的学生
who desire to pursue the course in depth.
提供指导。
It's called the course of miracles because
它被称为奇迹课程是因为
it's the miracle
奇迹
that is the central process whereby
是我们心灵得到治愈的
our minds are healed.
核心过程。
The course teaches us that the problem
这门课告诉我们，
is that we forgotten that we even have a mind
问题在于我们忘记了我们甚至有心灵，
and so it's like a valve amnesia
所以它就像一个已经落在我们身上
which has fallen across us
的阀门失忆症。
And we live in this world,
而我们活在这个世界上,
living our lives as a thorough set in quiet desperation,
在安静的绝望中过活,
never really knowing what the problem is.
从来不知道问题出在哪里。
So we have lives
所以我们的生活
of pain, of suffering, of love and hate of ups and downs,
充满了痛苦、苦难、起起伏伏的爱与恨,
but never knowing that
但从不知道
the source of all of our problems was
我们所有问题的根源在于
in a choice that our mind has made.
我们的心灵所做出的选择。
And what the miracle does is restore to our mind the awareness
奇迹所做的是在我们的心灵中恢复觉知,
that was the No.1 we do have in mind
觉知是我们心灵中最重要的，
and that within this mind is a power of choice.
它在这个心灵中是一种选择的力量。
So before we have chosen the ego thought system
所以之前我们若选择了攻击、内疚和恐惧
of attack and guilt and fear,
的小我思维体系,
now we could choose the thought system of the holy spirit
那么现在我们可以选择圣灵的思想体系，
and learn how to forgive and how to love.
学习如何宽恕，如何去爱。
The central concept
奇迹课程的
of a course of miracles is forgiveness.
核心概念是宽恕。
And there's a beautiful line
这里有一个美丽的
which really summarizes this,
语句很好地概括了这一点,
that says, the holiest spot on all the earth
也就是说，世界上最神圣的地方
is where an ancient hatred
就是古老的仇恨变成了
has become a present love.
现在是爱的地方。
At the holy spot on earth is not a place,
地球上的圣地不在某一个地方,
it is not a church, it is not a shrine,
不在教堂，也不在神殿,
it's the altar within our minds
当我们经历了可拍的委屈，
when we choose finally to forgive somebody
我们最终选择再次宽恕某人时，
again soon we've had a terrible grievance.
这便是我们心中的祭坛。
And by asking Jesus for help,
通过向耶稣求助,
we're able to shift the way that we see this person
我们可以改变对这个人的看法，
and so instead of his becoming an ancient enemy,
因此他不但没有成为老敌人，
he now suddenly becomes our friend
他现在突然成了我们的朋友、
and our brother and our companion back home.
我们的兄弟和我们的同伴。
I think the course is so important because
我认为这个课程非常重要，
it has a different type of spirituality
因为它具有一种与众不同的灵性路径，
than other paths because you don't have to leave
因为你不用离开
the world or your situation or your family or your job,
这个世界、你的处境、你的家庭或者你的工作，
you can stay right put where you are and practice the course,
你可以原地不动地操练这门课,
you don't have to go off to a mountain
你不必去山上
or in ashram or monastery,
或修行会所、或修道院,
because the main teaching of the course is forgiveness.
因为这门课的主要教学内容是宽恕。
And so you practice these lessons of forgiveness
所以你在学习过程中，
as you go along with the course,
在你的生活、工作和家庭生活中
day by day, minute by minute, in your life
日复一日、每时每刻
in your job and your family.
操练宽恕这个课程。
And you have as the course teaches us a right mind,
正如课程教导我们的，我们有了正知,
where there is a correction for each
在那里有对小我思想体系中
wrong mind of thought of the ego thought system.
每个错误思想的修正。
And so as I'm going through my day
因此当我在一天中
and I feel myself getting upset and angry,
感到自己变得沮丧和愤怒时,
I have an internal teacher
我有一个内在老师，
that the course says
课程说是
is either Jesus or the holy spirit
耶稣或圣灵，
and I can ask for help
我可以请求帮助，
and in that instant I can shift my perception.
在那一刻我可以改变我的看法。
And that's what the course calls a miracle.
这就是课程所说的奇迹。
And I can have that anger changed to a new perception
我可以让这种愤怒转变成一种新的感知，
and let it go
通过在课程中称之为
through this process that course calls forgiveness.
宽恕的过程来放下它。
When I started to read a course of miracles
当我开始阅读奇迹课程
and recognize that to forgive is to overlook.
并认识到 "宽恕就是视而不见。"
That selective remembering
这种选择性的记忆
helped in the process of forgiveness
帮助我们在宽恕的过程中
to choose only the thoughts of love
只选择慈爱的念头
and forget those of aggression,fear, denial,anger.
而忘记攻击、恐惧、否定和愤怒的念头。
That in that attitude
这种基于
based upon a spiritual concept
灵性概念的态度认为，
that we are not our bodies
我们不是我们的身体，
but we are in truth spirit.
我们事实上是灵性。
At that point I could understand
在这一点上，
what the course meant, when it said,
我可以理解课程的意思，当它说到：
to forgive is not to condone,
宽恕不是纵容，
it's not to make error real,
不是让错误成为现实，
but rather to recognize that
而是要认识到
rather to recognize that what you thought someone has done to you,
你认为别人对你所做的事情，
has never in truth occurred.
实际上从未发生过。
Has never in truth occurred was so struggling to me
从来没有发生过的事对我来说是如此的挣扎，
because of course it occurs,
因为它当然发生了,
we see it every day,
我们每天都能看到,
we experience it every moment,
我们每时每刻都在经历,
but in truth it's saying, in the metaphysical reality,
但事实上，在形而上学的现实中,
in the spiritual truth,
在灵性真相中,
in God's world,
在上主的世界里,
it has not occurred.
它从未发生过。
Only by shifting our thought
只有将我们的思想
from the ego's thought system to that of God,
从小我的思想体系转移到上主的思想体系,
can we dare to accomplish forgiveness.
我们才敢于完成宽恕。
That's the bad news.
这是坏消息。
The good news is we have a friend,
好消息是我们有个朋友,
the voice within us,
我们的内在之声、
the eternal forgiver,
永恒的宽恕者、
the higher guide, the higher self
指导灵、高我，
anything we choose to call it.
不管我们怎么称呼它。
And it's that, that great transformer within
正是这种内在的巨大变化，
that helps in the process of forgiving.
有助于我们学会宽恕。
So it became been
所以它变成了
very very specific the guidelines
进行宽恕的
I was given forgiveness.
非常非常具体的指导方针。
No.1, recognize I had a problem,
第一，承认我有问题,
that I wasn't feeling peaceful
我感觉不到安宁，
and that I was holding
我对某人
a negative feeling about someone,
有负面情绪,
recognize it, bring it to the surface,
承认它，让它浮出水面,
confront it,
面对它,
all within myself, of course.
当然，这一切来自于我自己。
And the second,
第二,
recognized that I wanted peace,
认识到我想要平安,
that I really wanted to see it differently,
我真的想以不同的方式看待它,
but I wanted to change my mind.
我想改变我的想法。
I didn't want to hold this grudge, this grievance any longer.
我不想再怀着这种怨恨与委屈了。
No.3,
第三,
know that I couldn't accomplish this by myself,
我知道我一个人做不到,
meaning my small self, my ego self.
也就是说我渺小的自我，我的小我做不到。
No.4, turn it over to the higher self,
第四，把它交给高我,
say, take this mess, I can't handle it.
说，看看这个烂摊子，我处理不了。
I really surrender it to you.
我真的臣服于你。
I ask you to take it from me.
我请求你把它从我这里拿走。
And to show me what true vision is.
并让我知道什么是慧见。
Now, when that happens,
现在，当这种情况发生时,
one can be sure that the situation is transformed,
可以肯定的是，情况已经发生了变化,
that one does see with different eyes.
那个人的目光已经不一样了。
I call it realize.
我称之为认出。
I begin to realize
我开始认出另一个人
what that other human being is to me,
对我来说意味着什么,
more than a brother or a sister,
不仅仅是兄弟姐妹,
more than a friend,
不只是朋友，
that person is myself.
那个人就是我自己。
In that sense I am not my brother's caper.
从这个意义上说，我不是我弟兄的俘虏，
I am that other.
我就是那个人。
No one can do anything to one's self,
当一个人通过
when one is looking
高我看这个世界时,
at the world through one's higher self.
没有他人可以对一个人的自我做什么。
And that becomes a system of such safety and protection
这就形成了一个安全和保护的系统，
that it has great dividends.
它有很大的好处。
The course has a very
这个课程有一个
unusual way of defining forgiveness
定义宽恕的非同寻常的方式。
And that is that you forgive your brother
那就是你宽恕你的兄弟
for what he has not done,
没有做的事情，
not for what he has done,
而不是宽恕他做过的事情，
which is the usual way of looking at forgiveness.
而这是看待宽恕的通常方式。
And what that means a one very important level
而这意味着一个非常重要的层面是，
is that what I choose you of
我选择你的和
and what I hold against you
我反对你的原因是，
is that it's because of you that I no longer
正是因为你，
experience the love with a peace of god
我不再体验到在你进入我的生活之前，
that before you came into my life and before you said
在你说或做这种华而不实的事情之前的
or did this waffle thing.
那种带着上主的平安之爱。
I felt wonderful
我感觉很好，
and all of a sudden my life has crumbled
突然间我的生活崩溃了，
and it's your fault.
这都是你的错。
And what the course helps us to understand
另一方面，
on the other hand
这门课程帮助我们理解到，
is that there's no one and nothing in this world
这个世界上没有任何人也没有任何事
that has the power to take odds peace away from me
有能力夺走我的平安，
except my own mind
除非我的心灵
if I choose to see myself as separate from it.
选择将自己与之隔离。
And so therefore what I forgive you for
所以我宽恕你的原因是
is that you have not taken the peace of God away from me,
因为你没有从我手中夺走上主的平安，
instead what I have to do is to forgive myself because
相反，我要做的是宽恕自己，
it was my mistaken choice
因为是我的错误选择造成了
that caused me all the pain
我所有的痛苦，
and not something you have done.
而不是你所做的。
And what allows us to do this
使我们能够做到这一点的是
is the role of Jesus or the holy spirit
耶稣或者说是圣灵这个角色，
that basically what Jesus says to us
基本上耶稣在我们心中对
in our minds is take my hand,
我们说的就是，抓住我的手,
use my eyes and look at your brother the way
用我的目光看待你的兄弟，
that I see him
就像我看他一样，
and then you see that this person is just like you,
然后你就会发现这个人就像你一样,
he shares the same insanity you do,
他和你一样疯狂,
he's part of the same
他和你是
40 thought system that you are part of
同一个思想体系的一部分，
and that he also yearns as you do to return home.
他也和你一样渴望回家。
And so rather than seeing my brother or my sister
因此，我并没有把我的兄弟姐妹
as separate and different for me
看作是独立的个体，
I see them as people walking along the
而是把他们看作是和我一样
same road back to heaven as I am.
沿着同一条通往天堂的道路行走的人。
And it's the love of Jesus which really helps us
正是耶稣的爱帮助我们实现了
make that shift.
这一转变。
What could you want
"你所要的东西，
forgiveness cannot give？
有什么是宽恕所不能给的？
Do you want peace?
你想要平安吗？
Forgiveness offers it.
宽恕会给你平安。
Do you want happiness，
你想要幸福、
a quiet mind,
平安的心、
a certainty of purpose
明确的目标、
and a sense of worth and beauty that transcends the world ?
超越世界的尊严与美感吗？
Do you want care and safety,
你想要得到更新，感到安全，
and the warmth of sure protection always?
以及随时受到稳妥的保护那种温馨的感觉吗？"
All of this, forgiveness offers you.
宽恕会给你这一切。
Forgive the world，
"宽恕世界吧。
and you will understand that
你就不难明白，
everything that God created cannot have an end.
上主所创造的一切，是没有终结的；
And nothing he did not create is real.
凡不是祂所造之物，都不是真实的。
In this one sentence is our course explained.
这一句话足以说明本课程的宗旨。"
There certainly does appear to be
在我们这个时代，
a spiritual awakening going on in our age.
确实出现了一种灵性上的觉醒。
I certainly
我对比
contrast the nineties with the forties and fifties
90年代和40、50年代，
when I grew up，
当我长大的时候，
things are so much different,
世界已变得不一样了,
God is no longer a dirty word,
上主不再是一个肮脏的字眼,
angels are spoken about freely,
天使被自由谈论，
miracles have talked about.
奇迹也不绝于耳。
And I sort of feel that the course
我觉得这个课程是
is like an integral part of that new movement.
就像是新运动的不可或缺的一个组成部分。
And in that way I think it's extremely important
从这个角度来说，
to mention something that the course is
我认为在教师手册的开头，
says of itself at the beginning of the teachers manual.
提到这个内容是非常重要的。
And that is that it's not the only spiritual path
这并不是唯一的灵性之路,
in fact, it says that it's only one path among
在手册中说到，这个方法实际上
many thousands of the universal course.
只是八万四千法门的一门。
And I think that that's extremely important
我认为这点非常重要，
to mention so that people don't believe
这样人们就不会相信
that the course is just another
这门课程只是
dogmatic set of teachings
另一套教条式的教义，
and that we're seeing the birth of a new church.
而且我们看到了一座新教堂的诞生。
And Jesus nicola says
耶稣还说，
also that he's not the only person
他不是唯一从
who is awaken from the dream
梦中醒来的人，
and that he's not the only helper.
也不是唯一的帮助者。
And that there are dozens and dozens and dozens
有很多很多很多的帮助者，
but he is one major symbol for us in the western world,
但是他是西方世界的一个主要象征。
And the course in miracles,
另外我认为奇迹课程,
I think there's a major expression
他的教诲对我们所有人
of his teachings to all of us.
都有重要的表达。
Beyond the body,
"当你放眼望去，
beyond the sun and stars,
你会看见一道弧形的金光，
past everything you see and yet somehow familiar
随着你的视线，
is an ark of golden light,
超越身体之上，超越了星尘与太阳，
that stretches as you look
超越你眼前似曾相识的一切，
into a great and shining circle.
逐渐拓展为一道灿烂伟大的光环。
And all the circle fills with light before your eyes.
那道圆环在你眼前光明灿烂。
The edges of the circle disappear
环的边界逐渐消褪，
and what is in it is no longer contained at all.
再也拦不住环内的光明。
The light expands and covers everything,
光线开始向外延伸,
extending to infinity,
须臾也无间歇地笼罩了整个天地万物，
forever shining and with no break or limit anywhere.
延伸至无穷无尽。
Within it everything is joined in perfect continuity.
万物在它内完美地交融为一体。
Nor is it possible to imagine that
你无法想象任何东西
anything could be outside,
可能置身其外，
for there is nowhere that this light is not.
因这光明无所不在。"  (T-21.I.8:1)
What is a miracle,
"所谓奇迹,
but this remembering?
不正是这个记忆吗？
And who is there in whom this memory lies not?
有谁心内没有这个记忆？
The light in one awakens it in all.
一个人心中的光明足以唤醒所有人的记忆。
And when you see it in your brother,
你只要能在一位弟兄身上身上看见光明,
you are remembering for everyone.
就等于为所有的人忆起了生命真相。" (T-21.I.10:4)